<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>

    <!-- Main Titles -->
    <string name="app_name">Planets</string>

    <!-- Action Bar Titles -->
    <string name="action_about">About</string>
    <string name="action_settings">Settings</string>

    <!-- Sources -->
    <string name="button_1">Source 1</string>
    <string name="button_2">Source 2</string>
    <string name="button_3">Source 3</string>
    <string name="button_4">Source 4</string>
    <string name="button_5">Source 5</string>

    <!-- Objects Names -->
    <string name="sun_title">Sun (Sol)</string>
    <string name="sun_sub_title_1">Specific Information:</string>
    <string name="sun_description">Age: 4.6 Billion Years\nType: Yellow Dwarf (G2V)\nDiameter: 1,392,684 km\nCircumference at Equator: 4,370,005.6 km\nMass: 1,989,100,000,000,000,000,000 billion kg (333,060 x Earth)\nSurface Temperature: 5500 °C</string>
    <string name="sun_sub_title_2">General Information:</string>
    <string name="sun_description_2">One million Earths could fit inside the Sun.
If a hollow Sun was filled up with spherical Earths then around 960,000 would fit inside. On the other hand if these Earths were squished inside with no wasted space then around 1,300,000 would fit inside. The Suns surface area is 11,990 times that of the Earth’s.

Eventually, the Sun will consume the Earth.
When all the Hydrogen has been burned, the Sun will continue for about 130 million more years, burning Helium, during which time it will expand to the point that it will engulf Mercury and Venus and the Earth. At this stage it will have become a red giant

The Sun will one day be about the size of Earth.
After its red giant phase, the Sun will collapse, retaining its enormous mass, but containing the approximate volume of our planet. When this happens, it will be called a white dwarf.

The Sun contains 99.86% of the mass in the Solar System.
The mass of the Sun is approximately 330,000 times greater than that of Earth. It is almost three quarters Hydrogen, whilst most of the remaining mass is Helium.

The Sun is an almost perfect sphere.
There is only a 10 kilometre difference in its polar diameter compared to its equatorial diameter. Considering the vast expanse of the Sun, this means it is the closest thing to a perfect sphere that has been observed in nature.

Light from the Sun takes eight minutes to reach Earth.
With a mean average distance of 150 million kilometres from Earth and with light travelling at 300,000 kilometres per second, dividing one by the other gives us an approximate time of 500 seconds, or eight minutes and 20 seconds. Although this energy reaches Earth in a few minutes, it will already have taken millions of years to travel from the Sun’s core to its surface.

The Sun travels at 220 kilometres per second.
The Sun is 24,000-26,000 light years from the galactic centre and it takes the Sun 225-250 million years to complete an orbit of the centre of the Milky Way.

The distance from the Sun to Earth changes throughout the year.
Because the Earth travels on an elliptical orbit around the Sun, the distance between the two bodies varies from 147 to 152 million kilometres. The distance between the Earth and the Sun is called an Astronomical Unit (AU).

The Sun is middle-aged.
At around 4.5 billion years old, the Sun has already burned off about half of its store of Hydrogen. It has enough left to continue to burn Hydrogen for approximately another 5 billion years. The Sun is currently a type of star known as a Yellow Dwarf

The Sun has a very strong magnetic field.
Solar flares occur when magnetic energy is released by the Sun during magnetic storms, which we see as sunspots. In sunspots, the magnetic lines are twisted and they spin, much like a tornado would on Earth.

The temperature inside the Sun can reach 15 million degrees Celsius.
At the Sun’s core, energy is generated by nuclear fusion, as Hydrogen converts to Helium. Because hot objects generally expand, the Sun would explode like a giant bomb if it weren’t for its enormous gravitational force.

The Sun generates solar wind.
This is a stream of charged particles, which travels through the Solar System at approximately 450 kilometres per second. Solar wind occurs where the magnetic field of the Sun extends into space instead of following its surface.</string>
    <string name="mercury_title">Mercury</string>
    <string name="mercury_sub_title_1">Specific Information:</string>
    <string name="mercury_description">Mass: 330,104,000,000,000 billion kg (0.055 x Earth)\nEquatorial Diameter: 4,879\nPolar Diameter: 4,879\nEquatorial Circumference: 15,329 km\nKnown Satellites: none\nNotable Satellites: none\nOrbit Distance: 57,909,227 km (0.39 AU)\nOrbit Period: 87.97 Earth days\nSurface Temperature: -173 to 427°C\nFirst Record: 14th century BC\nRecorded By: Assyrian astronomers</string>
    <string name="mercury_sub_title_2">General Information:</string>
    <string name="mercury_description_2">A year in Mercury is just 88 days long.
One day on Mercury lasts the equivalent of 176 Earth days. Mercury is nearly tidally locked to the Sun and over time this has slowed the rotation of the planet to almost match its orbit around the Sun. Mercury also has the highest orbital eccentricity of all the planets with its distance from the Sun ranging from 46 to 70 million km

Mercury is the smallest planet in the Solar System.
One of five planets visible with the naked eye a, Mercury is just 4,879 Kilometres across its equator, compared with 12,742 Kilometres for the Earth.

Mercury is the second densest planet.
Even though the planet is small, Mercury is very dense. Each cubic centimetre has a density of 5.4 grams, with only the Earth having a higher density. This is largely due to Mercury being composed mainly of heavy metals and rock.

Mercury has wrinkles.
As the iron core of the planet cooled and contracted, the surface of the planet became wrinkled. Scientist have named these wrinkles, Lobate Scarps. These Scarps can be up to a mile high and hundreds of miles long.</string>
    <string name="venus_title">Venus</string>
    <string name="venus_sub_title_1">Specific Information:</string>
    <string name="venus_description">Venus Description</string>
    <string name="venus_sub_title_2">General Information:</string>
    <string name="venus_description_2">Description 2</string>
    <string name="earth_title">Earth</string>
    <string name="earth_sub_title_1">Specific Information:</string>
    <string name="earth_description">Earth Description</string>
    <string name="earth_sub_title_2">General Information:</string>
    <string name="earth_description_2">Description 2</string>
    <string name="mars_title">Mars</string>
    <string name="mars_sub_title_1">Specific Information:</string>
    <string name="mars_description">Mars Description</string>
    <string name="mars_sub_title_2">General Information:</string>
    <string name="mars_description_2">Description 2</string>

</resources>